Alright, take two.
Alright.
I told you this was going to be very imperfect.
So we already fucked up the first time.
It was phenomenal.
Yeah.
The discussion?
The three minutes.
Absolutely amazing.
Sitting on via Jeff was excellent.
So we can always go longer.
Yeah.
A weird Brazilian guy is to blame for all of this.
So what is this going to be?
This is officially the second test recording slash teaser.
So tell me about it Pablo.
What is this going to be?
Well, it's a bit of an experiment where we're going to try to distill what we've learned, where we are.
And yeah, I think we, because mostly because of what we did with sovereign engineering so far, we now know a lot more than we did a year ago about where people get hung up.
And it's just the mistakes that keep coming up constantly or repeatedly.
So I think we're just going to walk and try to explore.
Yeah, it's a nice excuse to have a nice walk in the sun.
That's going to be my thing.
The reason why I'm doing this is I just want to have an excuse to see you once a week for an hour.
Because even though we are more or less at the same place, we basically never see each other.
So that's terrible.
And yeah, I just want to pick your brain.
I just want to see where things are at.
And I think you've been very close to Noster for a long time.
Probably closer than most.
And I just, yeah, probably too close.
Yeah, careful.
Don't fly too close to the sun.
No, but I, I, I, I mean, we talked about some of those things already.
And the last time we talked about it was like, we should actually record all this and just get other people involved and just see kind of how the conversation involves and open it up and so on.
And so we got because many in many of those conversations, we go in knowing less than we that we end up with.
We find out things while we are having a conversation as an exploration that we're having.
And I think we've arrived to many interesting thought provoking ideas, having those conversations.
Yeah.
And so we're going to continue and we're going to press record and we're going to just send it.
That's going to be the idea.
Yeah, exactly.
That's how that's how the internet evolves.
It used to be sent tweet, the secret to life and absolutely everything.
Now I guess it's like send note.
I still hate it.
I mean, I should, I think we should reclaim.
Yeah, fuck it.
But now it's going to be sent podcast.
Tolster.
Yeah, exactly.
And so that's what it's going to be.
And yeah, I'm a big believer in kind of, you know, that's why we, we also in the, in the cohorts, we force everyone to walk and talk and think out loud.
And so on.
And so that's, that's going to be an experiment in kind of, you know, I don't know.
Noster, development, dialogue, I think.
Something like that.
Yeah.
Well, let's see how it goes.
Let's see if that one worked.
Maybe we have to take a, do it take three.
We'll be loving something.
But yeah, no.
I hope, I hope we'll get something out of it.
I'm probably, we're probably going to do it mostly for ourselves.
I guess if someone listens via Jeff is going to listen.
Come on.
We're going to, we just have to do, like, hashtag starcraft or something.
It's going to be, it's going to be amazing.
It's going to be a Noster and Starcraft, but exactly.
There, we'll see, we'll see how it goes.
And yeah, we'll, we'll see where our feet and our conversations lead us.
So that's the plan.
That's the plan.
Awesome.