okay so let's see if I can do this well it's starting to rain now which isn't that
nice but you know I thought I'll go for a little evening walk and talk about the
concept of sovereign engineering so it worked reasonably well for the philosophy
I spoke about the philosophy and the concept for 45 minutes and kind of
managed to extract that philosophy from this recording by just talking through
it and thinking through it and so on and yeah now I kind of want to do the same
for the actual nuts and bolts concept of sovereign engineering so I'm not sure
where to begin I guess the right question to ask is what are the core pillars
of sovereign engineering and as it is now I think the core pillars are the weekly
loop the Friday demo days definitely the walks so the weekend walks and potentially now also
the captains even though the captains are relatively new concept but again as it is now we have six
weeks and six captains so yeah maybe we can see this also as another core pillar definitely the
fact that it is in person so again that's another core thing and yeah I'm not sure how to best
structure the concept what I want to do is basically create a playbook like some slides or
some things so that other people can do the same thing and really explain why we think this is
so I already mentioned when I talked about the philosophy that the walks for example the weekend
walks are incredibly important because what we want to have happen is a free flow of ideas and so
the walks are kind of the best way we have found to have this free flow of ideas other activities
work as well but nothing works as well as the walks and one participant mentioned it that
like for some reason walking really stimulates creative thought as far as I know there's a lot of
research around this and one participant summed it up nicely as like left foot right foot left
brain right brain so it really activates your brain it activates your whole being and so what we
are aiming for is light to moderate walks that go on for a little while like it should be at least
an hour or 90 minutes at a comfortable pace where you can just leisurely walk you're not gonna
break a sweat it's not gonna be super steep and you can walk next to each other and just have
a conversation so that's what we're aiming for that's that's kind of again the walks are a core
pillar of the summer and engineering concept and so what happens usually at the walks is that people
really get talking and really open up and really play around with crazy ideas and they bounce ideas
of each other and what's also very very nice with the walks is that the group mixes quite naturally
so usually we have around 21 participants that's what we're aiming for and if you
do the walks properly then the group will naturally mix so you will have
many many different conversational partners during a three hour walk and the way to do this is to have
two people that really know what they are doing that know how this concept works one in the one at
the very end and one in the front and they have to keep the group together and the person in the front
the guide so to speak in the front has to stop every 20 minutes or so you know to enjoy the view
to take a sip of water and to wait for the group to come together again and once the group is
completely together again just start walking again and we we continue and then usually what happens is
that if you if you if you still have something to hash out with the people you just talked you're
gonna continue to talk to the same people and if not then it's a great opportunity to just you know
continue and get to know someone else and talk about something else with someone else
so that really really works but again you have to have two guides one in the front and one in the
end that keeps the group together and you need to stop from time to time to make sure that
everyone catches up and the group kind of comes together again and so that you have can have this
natural kind of formation this natural group formation and this you know
these natural groups form and these conversations form so if you contrast this for example with
a large long table where everyone just sits it doesn't really work like if you sit for two or three
hours and have a dinner you have at most if you're lucky three conversational partners the person to
the left to you the person to the right to you and the person in front of you and it usually doesn't
mix so you usually stay put and you get food and so on and so forth so this is not very conducive
to you know what what we want to do so we try to avoid actually doing that so so we want to do
kind of different activities and yeah shout out to a way slice for example Josh who figured this
out and he who is organizing the Bitcoin beef steaks it's a similar idea where yes it revolves
around food and so on but one rule at the beef steaks is there is no sitting so everyone just stands
and eats with their hands and so you it's a very different dynamic and it just mixes
way nicer way better and people just you just run into each other and you have this natural
group formation as well so this definitely works as well for you know what we are trying to aim at
which brings me to the next kind of cornerstone the Fridays the demo days so after the demos
we usually have a barbecue and again like we try to do it in a beef steak style so that everyone
kind of stands we don't have you know like pre-arranged seating or anything and you just you know
go to the grill grab some food people are usually standing around in groups and just discussing
what was just shown during the demo days and the demo days are absolutely crucial to the sovereign
engineering concept so every Friday you have to demo something and it has to be actually
working code did you wrote or prompted into existence yourself and the idea is to try something
new try a crazy idea every week basically and show it off at the end of the week it might be related
to something you have already been working on it might be something completely new but it has to
be like we highly encourage to show something new every day to try a new idea every week excuse me not
every day but every week and yeah that's kind of the most important day of the sovereign engineering
weekly loop or the Friday demo days so again the whole idea of the whole program the whole idea of
the whole concept is to have a space and the time where massive ideation and experimentation can
happen so bring the best and brightest minds together let them exchange ideas let them iterate on
ideas let them iterate on the things they are working on things they are thinking through
and if you have a crazy idea just write out just straight away implement it and show it to the
group doesn't matter if it's half broken doesn't matter if it's half baked just give it a go give it
your best shot and show it on Friday that's kind of the core of the concept and every week is the
same so we have this weekly loop of show talk build and so Friday is show time on the weekends and
during the walks and in between sessions that's where the talking happens again like the the hikes
are structured and the the things that we do on the weekends and the things that we do as like
group activities are purpose built to have free flowing conversations and to have this kind of
spontaneous ideation happen yeah in the philosophy section I already talked about
this to really cognition and how it was influenced by the work of John Reveke who talks about
tapping into this distributed cognition a lot and basically the idea of the logos is not new
at all it's basically you know like you never know where the conversation leads you and the
conversation if it is a good conversation takes on the life of its own and that's exactly what you
want to see so there's a lot of research on this there's a lot of prior work so we are not
reinventing the wheel we're just trying to facilitate all these things that I just mentioned
so
all right so I mentioned the walks which are the walking and the talking is
a core absolute core pillar of the sovereign engineering concept the Friday demo day is kind of
where the rubber meets the road and the rest of the week has some structure as well so every day
except for Thursday is structured so we have Monday mornings Tuesday talks Wednesday workshops
Thursday is to the time off so Thursday time off and Friday festivities Friday is the demo day
and the barbecue and you know a little bit of a celebration afterwards that we made it through
the week so it's a very very intense six-week program and the what's happening on each day
should kind of be self-explanatory but I'm gonna go through the days a little bit in any case so
Monday mornings is a little bit of an orientation setting the tone of the week like the first week
I think is the most important one it's basically where people get to know the sovereign engineering
concept there's gonna be a little bit of an orientation a little bit of kind of explanation of how
this works what we expect how this is gonna go and every week on Monday you know we're gonna kind of
set the direction and as I explained in the philosophy section there is we use a lot of metaphors
around ships and shipping so we want to ship software we want to ship products and the ocean metaphor
also works really well because it is a wide unexplored cryptographic see that we are exploring
or we are trying to explore so the space that is opened up by Bitcoin and NOSR the cryptographic
space if you will I'll find entity and money is what we want to explore so yeah each Monday we are
trying to kind of set course in some direction and on Tuesday we have talks so Tuesday talks
is the second day of every week and we want to give participants the chance to give talks and
present things so this is where slides are shown this is where you can talk about you know whatever
you think is relevant we the organizers might talk about some things as well especially in the first
week and as I mentioned before every week has a dedicated captain so the captain might give a
talk there as well the captain is the person who basically steers the ship through each week so
every week has a dedicated captain so we have six weeks and we have six captains there's one caveat
week number five is also time off it's like an off week because the program is quite intense
we learned over time that we need a week off and week five I think it is week five or is it week four
I'm not sure week four or week five is the week off it might be week four like the in the middle
basically anyway as you can tell you know like that's why I'm talking into the microphone because I'm
trying to write down and figure out the concept and we we didn't really do this yet so this exercise
is very much needed but anyway I mentioned the Monday mornings I mentioned the Tuesday talks
on Wednesday with workshops so Wednesday workshops that's where the hands on stuff is happening if you
want to show someone how to you know like set up a certain server that you use or
assemble a certain piece of hardware that you frequently use or if you want to show someone
something in terms of how to configure this how to compile this how to do this or that so we had
people you know like you know play around with machine networks play around with synchronization tools
play around with Noster Relays like how to set up your own Noster Relay how to set up your own
blossom server how to do all the things that we are interested in and if you are new and if you're
coming from the outside and if you know Noster is new to you for example or some aspects of Bitcoin
or Lightning or eCache are new to you the workshops are a great way to really get up to speed and have
some of the best people in the world teach you how to properly do this so again Wednesday workshops
those are the hands on hands on sessions and anyone can give a workshop the captain it's the
captain's job to basically find the slots and set up the times and let everyone know when
workshop is happening and we also you know we do our best to arrange the rooms in a meaningful way
so if there's talks the room will be set up for talks if there's workshops the room will be set up
for workshops if there's demos on Friday the room will be set up for demos so we rearrange the
surrounding accordingly to what we want to do all right so where are we?
Monday mornings I explained that orientation and so on Tuesday talks I explained that as well
Wednesday workshops I went through that as well Thursday time off again six weeks are in
Madera it's a beautiful place Thursday is some time to explore or some time to you know get
some experiments implemented or refine some of the things you're working on your choice and Friday again
is where the rubber hits the road Friday festivities Friday is demo day and we have demo day usually
starting right off the lunch and yeah we time box aggressively so it's usually six minutes of
demo time and two minutes of discussion time and yeah because if you do like 20 plus demos in
an afternoon you have to time box aggressively we take breaks after you know like six or seven demos
or so so we usually have three sessions of seven people or something like that and like three
sessions of seven demos and still gonna take a while it usually takes a couple hours and after that
we usually done like five p.m six p.m something like that six p.m usually and we'll have barbecue
and the barbecue goes on for you know as long as we wanted to so we'll have great food
Martaine is our chef and he you know cooked some some great steak and some yeah just tasty tasty
barbecue there's something for everyone and you know after demo day we usually also invite
friends and family and you know some outside people if they want to have a bite and kind of hang
out with the crew and discuss kind of what's happening here and so on but in general in general
and that's also a core part of the project of the concept so a core thing of the concept is that
this is a private off the record event I want to repeat that again because it is really important
that this is a private off the record event you cannot you cannot do proper thinking completely
out in the open like you you have to be able to think in private and communicate in private and
basically you know just you don't want the online mob to come after you just because you had a
crazy weird stupid idea so yeah we we want to keep the group close then together so we don't
want to have any outside people there is also always the risk of having having spooks or having
just straight up weird people and so on and yeah so so that's super important as well it's like
we we definitely want to build out in the open and you know like we we care deeply about open
source and the open source philosophy but when it comes to ideation and experimentation you have
to be able to to do it in a safe space so to speak like you have to do it with your peers you have
to basically in some sense you only want criticism from people that are actually on your side
yeah because otherwise you'll you might destroy a gem of an idea too early you know in the
you you you I think this is a really important part and in part also because we had some
bad experiences with bringing outside people into the group to early and those kind of things like
it just destroys the dynamic and it destroys the trust that was built over over the weeks and so on
so again private off the record event super important um because otherwise you can't do
any kind of unconstrained thinking in some sense if you're always worried that there might be
yeah well you know an enemy an enemy in the midst of us so to speak then then you you won't allow
yourself to to kind of go all out and and actually discuss some of the more crazy ideas that you
have and so on so yeah um well else what else is there to say
again to summarize it for myself the core pillars as I see them are the walks so they're walking
we can't walk the show talk build loop so the weekly loop is kind of the core of the concept
six weeks six captains that's another pillar actually be together in person for a long time
and don't kind of dictate what's going to happen top down but let it organically emerge
and kind of having a different person leading the group and leading the program for every week
really helps with that um yeah and kind of the whole concept is geared towards the free flow of
information ideation and experimentation that's kind of what we what we care about
yeah I don't think I forgot anything crucial we usually also do an opening
ritual in some sense so we also want to go into each week with some intentionality we definitely
want to go into each cohort with intentionality so we usually do a reflective contemplative exercise
at the very beginning so I usually ask participants what they want to see built kind of have them
contemplate where they came from what annoys them what is like really broken in in their eyes
in like if they look at the internet from through their lands what's the one thing they really
want to fix and kind of also think long and hard about not only what is broken but also how could
you fix it so what is an actionable thing that you could do what is something that you could come
up with that would actually move the needle that would actually make the internet about a place
yeah so so that's usually part of the opening ritual and we have a closing ritual as well where we
kind of look back at the six weeks a lot of things can happen in six weeks and kind of contrasted
to our state of mind and our thoughts and where we were in the world six weeks ago at the beginning
of the cohort yeah I think that's kind of it
I might keep the microphone on a little longer usually stuff still comes up
at least it stopped raining so it's actually a nice walk now
yeah we we also want to encourage participants to actually be present with each other actually
being a moment don't be on the phone all the time you know actually spend time together actually
participate participate in the program fully be present fully go on the walks you know leave
your phone at home or put it into airplane mode or what have you and really hashing out
in the real world with real people and you know if the if the idea is really really good
you won't have to write it down like it will stay with you or someone else will like it will
stay with someone else so that's what we found usually so we try to stay away from too many
distractions sent too much online time and so on but yeah what else
I guess the fact that it is in Madera in a small like
island in the middle of the Atlantic is kind of important as well for two reasons so
you can't leave it takes quite a bit to get there so there is kind of a filter in terms of
if you want to come there you actually have to fly there there is no other way I mean you can come
come with a container ship but that's even more trouble so you can't just like swing by and then
leave again you actually if you want to participate you'll have to participate and we also
you know we we we will make exceptions for exceptional people if they only can come for like a
week or two but the point of the program is to stay for the full six weeks like you'll get the
most out of it if you stay for the full six weeks and what's amazing about Madera is not only
is it beautiful and not only is it like a laid back you know like it's a magical place kind of it's
quite topologically speaking it's just ridiculous it's a volcanic island subtropical it has all
these you know dark volcanic cliffs it has like black beaches um well one black beach I don't
I don't want I don't want to get the hopes in terms of beaches up too high um there isn't many
beaches there's two artificial ones and one or two like black ones but um well I love the place
it's a it's a it's a fantastic place to to live and to be and what's amazing about Madera is
that thanks to the efforts of Andre and free Madera and everyone who helps there like shout out to
Charlie who is onboarding all the merchants and so on um there is 150 plus merchants on the
island accepting Bitcoin and so that's quite something and just it's so normal to pay in Bitcoin
in Madera I pay my breakfast lunch in dinner in Madera basically you know every day and you know
like you go to the barber you paint Bitcoin you go to the dentist to paint Bitcoin you have really
nice dinner you paint Bitcoin um there's so many merchants that accepted it's such a normal thing
like I don't even think about it too much anymore and the reason why this is amazing is because
and we had this happen in in various cohorts people will you know build a new wallet or build like
crazy you can't have wallet or what have you or build a new nasa thing or when we came up with
nut saps you know like you can implement it and the next day go to the coffee shop grab a coffee
and pay it with the wallet you just you know built yesterday and it works and you just like it's
such an amazing feeling to be able to do that and in some way you can alpha test the future in Madera
so not only like the goal of the of of sovereign engineering is to to build a future that you want to
see we want to help you build the future that you want to see and Madera is a fantastic
breeding ground because there's just awesome people there there's many Bitcoin us there and the
merchant adoption is just like through the roof so um it's a great place to run a sovereign
engineering cohort so I think that's quite important actually that if you want to run a sovereign
engineering cohort it should be in a place that is like super super Bitcoin friendly and just like
in the best case you can just you know go somewhere and buy coffee with Bitcoin and just again like
test the wallet you build yesterday and so on so yeah that's kind of a part of the concept as well
like it should be like um in some sense the reason why it works I think is because if you bring
21 people together 21 the coins together with the that are value aligned then have to write value
set and they are in a place that is like super Bitcoin friendly and just awesome and beautiful
and you know allows for kind of
allows for the spontaneous creation of new things and the the spawning of new ideas then magical things
are bound to happen and yeah that's why we're doing it the reason why we're doing sovereign
engineering is because we want to see awesome stuff being built we want to expand the impact
that freedom tech can have we want to come up with new ideas we want to come up with new protocols
we want to come up with new ways of doing things we want to test them out immediately we want to
kind of you know have an iron sharpen sharpen's iron situation and we want to have a good time
while we're doing it so um yeah that's kind of the idea and it really works so it really works so
far we're gonna start with cohort number five very very soon so there's still a month or so left
a little over a month so if all of that sounds interesting please go to sovereignengineering.io
and apply for the cohort if we like what we see if we like what you've built in the past um we will
we will take you we will say yes to you so we are very open we don't have any requirements any
official requirements we just want to be surrounded by people and invite people that know what
they are doing that want to that are value aligned that want to see more cool stuff built
and yeah that's kind of it and with that I guess I'll take another breather not sure if I'll
switch off the mic yet but yeah I might leave it at that
all right one more very final thought so it might be important to note that the concept is
of course not set in stone at all so it evolved with every single cohort in like 12 to 18 months
from now it might look a little bit different again but that's kind of what we landed on we had
the weekly loop from the get go so quite a few things did not change but we're still kind of figuring
out the best way to do this as we speak and so this shouldn't be seen as gospel but just as kind of
a snapshot in time maybe if you will so this is how we're doing it right now we know it works
we are very confident that it's going to work again for the next one and yeah as long as it keeps
working we want to keep doing it so that might be an actual good place to stop